# Damiano Chintala

# **Applications Developer**

Highly skilled software and web development professional bringing more than 4 years in software design, development and integration. Offering advanced knowledge of JavaScript, C#, SQL and PHP programming languages. Experienced in writing code and developing systems for People Management applications.

### **Work Experience**

# Lead Software Developer

ProLearn Technology Limited

March 2020 - Present

Lusaka, Zambia

#### Duties include:

- Developing Google Apps Scripts for Operations, Sales and Human Resource Departments.
- Leading the team maintaining and improving the functionalities for company POS, CRM and HRM applications.
- In charge of in house Software Development and Maintenance.
- Reviewing, modularising and updating old code bases to modern development standards, reducing operating costs and improving functionality.
- Leading version control efforts for the organisation, employing GitHub and other public and open source repositories.

# Volunteer IT Head of Department

Posterity Zambia

November 2019 - Present

Lusaka, Zambia

#### Duties include:.

- Supervising IT Support staff.
- In charge of Website Development and maintenance.
- Setting up virtual meetings and Webinars.
- · Overseeing data collection and entry.

#### **Contact Details**

Phone: +260-770-553-227

Email: damianochintala@gmail.com

Visit:

https://damianosilverhand.github.io

Twitter: @ES6Maestro LinkedIn: <u>damianochintala</u>

## **Professional Skills**

Product development

Virtualisation

Programming

Search Engine Optimisation

API design knowledge

Code Review Management

Version Control Management

JavaScript Specialist

PHP Specialist

Python

Google Apps Script

Technical issues analysis

### **Project Management Tools**

Trello. Github.

Slack.

### **Personal Skills**

Team Worker

Team Leader

Good communicator

Detail orientated

# Fullstack Developer

## Hackers Guild

January 2018 - November 2019

Lusaka, Zambia

#### Duties included:.

- UI/UX Prototyping and Design.
- Frontend Website Development using ReactJS.
- Backend Development using MeteorJS, NodeJS, MongoDB and Firebase.
- · Mobile Applications Development using React Native.

# Back and Front Office Supervisor

D.A.T Trading (PUMA SUPER7)

March 2015 - January 2017

Kitwe, Zambia

#### Duties:

- Analyzed customer orders to identify errors and omissions, taking appropriate action to verify and retrieve critical account data.
- Produced monthly sales reports using advanced Excel spreadsheet functions.

Assisted team members with cashier functions, such as overrides, and retrieves alternate merchandise at the point of sale.

• Monitored cashiers' work and balanced registers to maintain strong financial controls.

#### Education

# **Bachelor in Frontend Development**

# OpenClassrooms

2020 - Present

Coursework includes:

Building Web Apps with ReactJS, Programming with JavaScript, Designing Relational Databases, Understanding The Web, Building REST APIs and Web Security.

# Advanced Certificate in Web Applications Development

### Hackers Guild Institute

February 2017 - December 2017

Coursework included:

Programming, Agile Project Management, Database Design, Web languages and Frameworks, and Backend Development.

### Grade 12 Certificate

Masala Secondary School

2004 - 2008

Coursework includes:

English Language, Mathematics, Pure Sciences and Biology.

### Certifications

- ☐ Agile Project Management | OpenClassrooms | 07/2021.
- ☐ Software Developer Path | LinkedIn Learning | 04/2021
- ☐ Cybersecurity with Cloud computing | LinkedIn Learning | 02/2021
- □ Software Engineering Virtual Work Experience | JPMorgan Chase & Co | 02/2021.
- ☐ CNSS Certified Network Security Specialist | ICSI UK | 05/2020
- Building Web Projects With REST APIs | OpenClassrooms | 02/2020.
- Relational Database Logic Model Design | OpenClassrooms | 02/2020 .
- ☐ Project Management | OpenClassrooms | 02/2020.
- ☐ Workforce Collaboration and Development | YALI | 10/2016.

#### Referees

- Mr Michael Habanyama
   Operations Manager
   ProLearn Technology
   info@zamfind.technology
   +260764000016
- Mr Aaron Sichone
   Head Of Operations
   Posterity Zambia
   <u>aaron@posterityzambia.te</u>
   <u>ch</u>
  - +260973914712
- Mr Abednego Mwanza
   Head of Training
   Hackers Guild
   overflow@hackersguild.or
   g
   +260978553568

### **Affiliations**

- 1. Information and Communications Technology Association of Zambia.
- 2. World Organisation of the Scout Movement.
- 3. Facebook Developers Circle: Lusaka.

### **Leadership Roles**

- 1. President, CESCU, The Copperbelt University.
- 2. Secretary, Students Judiciary Committee, The Copperbelt University.
- 3. Vice Chairperson, Provincial Rover scout Council, Copperbelt Province.
- 4. Scout Leader, 54th Ndola Scout Group, Zambia Scouts Association.